[calm] Hi I'm Jeffrey and for the last
five years I've been building Aesthetic
Computer a creative computing system that treats the
personal computer itself as an unfinished instrument
It's three things at once an operating system
you can boot a laptop into a programming
language called KidLisp and a social network where
people make art together
The whole stack is free and open source
nineteen thousand commits in with seventeen thousand
KidLisp programs and twenty-eight hundred handles drawing
chatting and composing in real time
With LLM-powered development there's never been a better
time to write new software for old hardware
Windows 10 end-of-life just stranded hundreds of millions
of laptops and strip away the consumer operating
system and those machines become a planetary population
of half-built instruments waiting for a kernel
For the LACMA Art and Technology Lab we
propose growing Aesthetic
Computer into a public device library a lending
fleet of refurbished laptops flashed with our operating
system at fifty dollars per seat circulating through
Flash Days workshops and Family Play afternoons at
the museum
At the 2027 Symposium we boot the cohort
at the 2028 Demo Day we play the
room
The personal computer is a civic instrument and
a new scene is just beginning