Personal computers
have not been very personal.
Windows 10 end-of-life just stranded
hundreds of millions of laptops.
There has never been a better time
to develop new software for old hardware.
This is AC Native.
A bare-metal creative
computing operating system.
No desktop. No app store.
Fifty dollars per seat.
For the LACMA Art and Technology Lab,
we propose growing it into a public device library.
A lending fleet of AC Blank laptops
flashed with our OS.
Circulating through Flash Days, workshops,
and Family Play afternoons at LACMA.
A public waitlist.
The library welcomes artists flashing
their own custom creative operating systems,
joining a tradition of
artist-run device libraries.
Aesthetic Computer has been under
active development since 2021.
Over nineteen thousand commits.
Seventeen thousand KidLisp programs.
Twenty-eight hundred registered handles.
At the 2027 Symposium
we boot the cohort.
At the 2028 Demo Day
we play the room.
Aesthetic.Computer.
A civic instrument.