Personal computers have not been very personal
Windows 10 end-of-life just stranded hundreds of millions
of laptops
There has never been a better time to
develop new software for old hardware
Aesthetic
Computer can run as your whole operating system
on a laptop
No desktop no app store
Fifty dollars per seat
For the LACMA Art and Technology Lab we
propose growing it into a public device library
A lending fleet of AC Blank laptops flashed
with Aesthetic
Computer circulating through Flash Days workshops and
Family Play afternoons at LACMA
A public waitlist
The library welcomes artists flashing their own custom
creative operating systems joining a tradition of artist-run
device libraries
Aesthetic
Computer has been under active development since 2021
Over nineteen thousand commits
Seventeen thousand KidLisp programs
Twenty-eight hundred registered handles
People draw chat and compose pieces together in
real time
At the 2027 Symposium we boot the cohort
At the 2028 Demo Day we play the
room
Aesthetic dot Computer
A civic instrument
The new scene has just begun